Previously on AMC's
The Walking Dead...
전 휴먼지놈프로젝트 10인 중 한명이었어요
I was part of a 10-person team
at the Human Genome Project,
우리가 저 놈들 마지막 하나까지
몰아낼 수 있습니다
I believe we can take out every last
dead one of them.
불에는 불처럼요
Fire with fire.
저 뒤에서 숏 버스를 찾았어
We found a short bus out back.
- 지금이야말로 숨 좀 돌리면서...
- 우리가 숨 돌릴수록 느려질뿐이야
- Now that we can take a breath...
- We take a breath, we slow down...
우린 DC로 가야해, 지금 당장
We all need to leave to DC, right now.
우리가 네 목숨을 살렸어
We saved you.
그러니까 내가 지금 너희들을 살리려고 하는거라고
모두의 목숨을 말야
Well, I am trying to save yours.
Save everyone's.
남아서 도와주면
우리가 당신과 함께 가겠어
Stay and help us. And we will go with you.
♪ May the work I've done ♪
♪ Speak for me ♪
♪ May the work
I've done... ♪
점점 지저분해 지는것 같아
It's getting
a little messy for you.
♪ Speak for me... ♪
이제 은퇴할 땐가 보지
Gettin' ady for retirement.
여유를 찾고
몸에도 신경쓰면서 말야
Relaxin' the grooming standards.
배관공이나 해볼까 하는데
Thinkin' about
becomin' a plumber,
양치기나 되던가 아님 다른거라도
a sheepherder, or something.
당장에 그런 생각 할 필욘 없어요 아브라함
You ain't herdin'
sheep now, Abraham.
대의를 생각해야죠
Eyes on the prize.
맞긴 맞네
Damn right.
역시 내 여자답네
That's my girl.
내 전신을 면도하게 해줘야겠어
Maybe I'll let you
shave me down all over,
아주 매끈하게
dolphin-smooth.
오늘 밤에 밀어줄게요
(laughs)
I'll cut it for you tonight.
네 그렇게하시죠
Yes, ma'am.
그참에 로지타가
당신 머리도 다듬어 줄 수 있겠는데요?
Hey, maybe Rosita can give you
a trim while she's at it.
뒤에가 점점 난리가 나네요
Party's getting a little
long in the back.
아니면 머리가 무슨 힘의 원천이라도 돼요?
Or is it your source of power?
제가 곧 사자를 죽이는건 아닙니다
I ain't slayin' a lion
anytime soon.
제가 나귀의 턱뼈로 수 천명의 블레셋인을 죽이는 걸
I wouldn't be placing
any wagers on seein' me
봤다고 내기를 걸진 않을 겁니다
dispatch a thousand Philistines
with the jawbone of an ass.
그러니까 당신은 단지 세상을 구하기 위해
여기 온거네요?
Tara: Oh, so you'll just settle
on saving the world, right?
그래요
Yeah.
무슨 고민 있어요?
What's up?
- 지난 밤일 때문에요?
- 전혀요
- Last night?
- Nope.
그래요 그 일
또 내일 때문에요
Yes, that and tomorrow.
그리고 그 신부 때문에요
And I'm thinking
about that preacher,
그가 저질렀던 일들요
what he did.
♪ May the service I give ♪
♪ Speak for me... ♪
어쩌면 우리 바로 뒤에 있을지도 몰라
Maybe they're just behind us.
데릴과 캐롤이 돌아와서
Maybe Daryl and Carol came back.
지도를 살펴보고
차량를 구하고
Maybe they took the map,
found some cars,
그래서 길을 따라 오고 있을도 몰라
and they're just down the road.
따라 올거야
They'll catch up.
우리가 그들을 위해서
길을 치워주며 가고 있잖아
We're clearing the way for 'em.
얼마나 걸리겠어요?
Maggie:
How long will it be?
도착하게 되면 무슨 일을 하게 되는거죠?
After you get on that terminal
and do what you have to do?
몇 가지 요인들에 따라서요
Depends on a number of factors
세계 각지의 목표지점에
including density
of the infected
감염 정도가 어느만큼이냐에
따라서 결정될겁니다
around target sites worldwide.
잠깐만요, 목표 지점이라구요?
Wait, target sites?
지금 미사일을 쏘겠다고 말하는겁니까?
Are you talking about missiles?
그건 기밀이오
That's classified.
우린 이제 서로
그 정도는 넘었다고 생각했는데
Glenn: I thought
we were over that.
만약 우리가 다 살아있다면요?
What if we all live?
그 기밀이 문제가 되겠어요?
The secrets will matter then?
문제가 될 겁니다
They might.
어쨋든, 정상화 되는데
걸리는 속도는
Anyway, the speed
with which things normalize
몇가지 요인에 따라 결정될겁니다
depend on a number of factors
세계 기후 패턴과
including worldwide
weather patterns,
물론 그건 추정치를 제외한
모델이어야 하구요
which were modeled
without the assumption
차량, 비행기, 보트, 기차들은
that cars, planes,
boats, and trains
더 탄화수소를 내선 안됩니다
wouldn't be pouring hydrocarbons
대기중으로 들어갈테니까요
into the atmosphere this long.
그게 기체전염성 병원균에 닿으면
Changed the game quite a bit
상당히 이 게임을 변화시킬테니까요
when it comes to
air-transmissible pathogens.
머리는 왜 그래요?
Why the hair?
제가 이걸 좋아하니까요
Because I like it.
어느 누구도 가위를
델 수 없을 겁니다
And no one is takin'
scissor or clipper to it
듣고 있습니까? 에스피노자?
anytime soon. Do you
hear me, Miss Espinoza?
그래요 분명하게 알아들었어요
- Yes, loud and clear.
- (group chuckles)
웃고 싶으면
마음껏 웃어요
Eugene: Y'all can
laugh all you want.
아무도 비웃지 않았어요
Maggie:
No one was makin' fun.
내가 만난 가장 똑똑한 남자가
내 머리를 좋아했죠
The smartest man I ever met
happened to love my hair.
인간지놈프로젝트의 디렉터이자
My old boss,
T. Brooks Ellis,
내 전 보스인
T.브룩스 엘리스가 그랬죠
the director
of the Human Genome Project.
그 분은 제 머리가
He said my hair
made me look like,
내가 재밌는 사람임을
and I quote, "a fun guy,"
내가 누군지 보여준다고 했어요
which I am.
그리고 난 삼손이 아니에요
I just ain't Samson.
- (loud bang)
- (brakes screeching)
Abraham:
Bitchnuts!
(loud bang)
♪ May the service I give ♪
♪ Speak for me ♪
♪ You remember this ♪
♪ The work I've done... ♪
(snarling)
(theme music playing)
한글자막 워키토끼
수정 금지 / 배포 제한
상업적 이용 금지
본 저작물의 저작권은 원저작권자 미국 AMC와 FOX사에 있습니다
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
(faint gurgling)
(gasping, gurgling)
(assailant panting)
(gurgling)
(squishes)
엘렌...
Ellen...
엘렌!
- Ellen!
- (walkers snarling)
(music continues
playing on radio)
유진!
Eugene!
유진, 괜찮아요?
Eugene, are you okay?
그 신부가...
The preacher...
또 다른 출구를 보지 않았죠
didn't see another way out.
잠깐 거기서 기다려, 알겠지?
You hold on, okay?
다른 사람들은 어때, 다들 괜찮아?
Everyone else, you all right?
-그래
- 괜찮아요
- Glenn: Yeah.
- Tara: Yes.
엔진에 불이 붙었어요
어서 여기서 나가야해요
Rosita: The engine's on fire.
We gotta get out of here.
좋아, 당신과 내가 나가서
먼저 놈들을 쓰러뜨려서
All right, you and I go
first, knock 'em back,
메기랑 로지타가 나올 수 있도록 해놓을게
clear the way for Maggie
and Rosita to get out,
그 다음에 모두 같이 덤비자구
알겠지?
then we all start
hitting them, okay?
그래 좋아
해치워버리지
Yeah, all right.
We'll do it live.
(walkers snarling)
- 타라
- 네?
- Tara?
- Yeah?
유진을 보호해주고
다 처리되면 그 때 나와
You cover Eugene,
come out when it's clear.
- 알겠어요
- 내 신호에 맞춰!
- Okay.
- On my go!
지금이야!
Go!
(walker snarling)
어서요
엿같고 무서운건 알지만
Come on. I know it
sucks and it's scary,
- 지금은 용감해져야할 때에요
- 하고 싶다고 되는게 아니에요
- but it's time to be brave.
- It isn't voluntary.
아니요 다른 방법이 없다면 그래야 돼요
It is, when you're
screwed either way.
다른 사람을 도울 수 있는 기회를
놓치지 말아요
So you cut through the choice
that might help somebody.
어서요
Come on.
내가 바로 뒤에 있을게요
I'm right behind you.
(snarling continues)
(walker snarling)
Whew.
유진을 살펴봐
어디 다치진 않았는지
Check Eugene, see if he's hurt.
괜찮아요
상처랑 좀 정신이 없을 뿐이에요
I'm fine. Just cuts
and dings is all.
확인해!
Check him!
- 그건 당신 피에요?
- 어 그래
- Maggie: Is that your blood?
- Yeah.
빌어먹을 상처가 다시 벌어졌어
Damn thing opened again.
거짓말안하고
상처는 쥐좆보다 작아
I swear, the cuts
are finer than frog's hair.
피만 많이 나는거야
They're just big bleeders.
구급상자는 버스 안에 있어요
Maggie:
First aid kit's in the bus.
뭐가 있나 찾아볼게요
I'll see what we have.
(rumbling)
(mutters)
우린 멈추지 않을거야
계속 갈거야
We're not stopping.
We're rolling on.
길을 따라 가다보면
다른 차를 찾을 수 있을거야
We'll find another vehicle
down the road.
임무는 변함없어
The mission hasn't changed.
전 반대에요
더는 안돼요
Devil's advocate,
nothing more--
우리는 아주 크게 충돌했어요
we smashed to a stop hard.
도로에서 벗어나려고 시간을 많이 소비했어요
We spent a lot of time rolling
things out of the road.
- 성당은 15마일 돌아가면 있어요
- 안돼
- The church is just 15 miles back that way--
- No.
우린 중단하지 않아
돌아가지도 않을거야
We don't stop.
We don't go back.
우린 전쟁중이야
후퇴는 다른 말로 패배일 뿐이야
We're at war,
and retreat means we lose.
다시 돌아가면
계획을 망치게 될 뿐이야
The road fights back,
the plan gets jacked.
우리 모두 그건 알지않나?
You all know that.
그럼 이제 계속 간다
그게 우리가 해야만 하는 일이니까
Now, we will get through
this because we have to.
이 바닥에서 확실한 건 없어
Every direction is a question.
우린 돌아가지 않을거야!
We don't go back!
이봐 잠깐만
너 괜찮은거야?
Hey, hey, hey.
You okay?
존나 멀쩡해
I am fit as a damn fiddle.
우린 너와 함께 갈거야
We are going with you.
여기서 명령은 네가 하잖아
You are calling this thing.
난 그냥 정말로
네가 괜찮은건지 알고 싶은거야
I just need to know you're good.
언제나 이런 식으로 멈추게 되잖아
This is how things stop.
지금은 그렇게 놔둘수 없어
세상은 그럴 여유가 없어
I can't afford that right now.
The world can't afford it.
있지 아까 충돌하면서
난 아주 세게 박았어
Listen, I took a pretty hard shot
to the sack with that crash.
저 지랄을 보자니
스트레스도 받았고 기분도 별로지만
I am stressed and depressed
to see that ride die,
하지만 네가 계속 가겠다고 한다면
but if you say we're rolling on,
난 좋아
I'm good.
계속 가지
We're rolling on.
엄살따윈 안 피우고
그냥 알아서 나아지겠지
I'm gonna rub some dirt
on it and walk it off.
그래
Yeah.
가면서 필요한게 있나 찾아보죠
Rosita: We'll find what we
need like we always have--
- 늘 그래왔듯이
- 좋아요
- on the way.
- Okay.
전 원래 엄살같은 거 안 떠는데요
I'm not rubbing dirt
on anything.
자전거를 찾아야 할까봐요
Maybe we can find some bikes.
적어도 불은 안나겠죠
Bikes don't burn.
좋았어
All right.
그래
Right.
(bus blast rumbles)
유진 뭐해요?
Rosita: Eugene,
what are you doing?
아무것도
Nothing.
갑시다
Rosita:
Let's go.
엘렌!
Ellen!
엘...?
Ell...?
엘렌?
Ellen?
엘렌
- (faint dripping)
- Ellen.
(glass clattering)
(crickets chirping)
가 보자고
Let's go.
(door creaks)
(humming)
(humming continues)
(crickets chirping)
(needle clatters)
이제 가서 망을 볼게
I'm gonna take a sweep.
알겠어요
Okay.
(thumps)
왔나
Hey.
어
고마워
Thank you.
뭐가?
(chuckles)
For what?
나와준 거
For showing up.
널 데리고 오는게 쉽지 않았는데
It took a little horse
trading to get you here,
이제 내가 왜 그랬는지 알겠네
but it's plain
as potatoes to me now.
무슨 말인지 알지?
You get it.
아까 사고난 후에 떠날 수도 있었는데
Coulda lit out after the crash,
넌 불평하지 않고 남아 주었어
made a case, but you stayed.
- 우린 거래를 했으니까
- 그래, 하지만 그걸 깰 수도 있었어
- I made a deal.
- Yeah, you coulda broke it.
내가 어떻게 해야 했을까?
(sniffs)
What was I gonna do?
오늘 밤에 그건
치워놔도 괜찮지 않겠어?
You gonna put that thing
away tonight?
그건 좀 어때?
붕대로 감아야지 않겠어?
How about that?
You gonna wrap that up?
괜찮아, 공기 좀 쐬게 하려고
No, I'm gonna
let it get some air.
성당서 못났던 지난 내 행동을
기억나게 해 주겠지
Got cut up pretty ugly last
night back at the church.
그렇겠지
Yeah.
이제 살아있는 모든 사람들이
강하다는 생각이 들어
Gotten to the point where
everyone alive is strong now.
우리도 그래야 하고
We have to be.
네가 강해서 그들과 서로 도울 수도 있고
아니면
You're either strong and they
can help you so you help them
그들이 강한 너를 죽일 수도 있어
or you're strong
and they can kill ya.
그러니까 그들을 죽여야 해
So you gotta kill them.
그들을 죽여아 해 그리고...
You gotta kill them and...
(sighs)
그게 쉽다고는 못하겠어
I want to say it's never easy.
사실이 아니니까
That's not the truth.
하지만 그게 지금 이 세상에서
가장 쉬운걸 어떡해
It's the easiest thing
in the world now.
세상은 바뀔거야, 그렇겠지?
The world's gonna change, right?
그래 맞아, 바뀔거야
You're damn right it's gonna.
잠 좀 자둬
이따 늦게 또 망봐야 하잖아
You'd better turn in.
You've got late watch.
그래
Yeah.
그 전에 난 엉덩이 맛 좀 보고
I really need some ass first.
굳이 말할 필욘 없었는데
그런다면야 뭐, 좋아
Didn't need to know
that, but, cool.
(panting)
아브라함!
Abraham!
유진이 또 지켜봐요
He's watching again.
자기개발 섹션에서요
Over there in the
self-help section.
(both laugh)
"자기개발이라니"
- Abraham: "Self-help."
- (both laughing)
신경쓰지마
Abraham: Don't worry
about him, baby.
해가되는 건 아니잖아
He's harmless.
- 느낌이 왔어요
- 보내줄게
- I'm already there.
- Come on.
(Rosita moaning)
이봐요
Dude.
카드가 책상위에 있어서
그걸 보고있었어요
Cards on the table,
I was watching them.
그래요, 나도 봤어요
Yeah, I saw that.
저들도 내가 가끔 본다는 걸
알고 있을거예요
I believe they know I catch
an eyeful on occasion,
저 사람들 문제라곤 말하지 않겠어요
하지만 내 잘못도 아닌걸요
which isn't to say it's their thing.
It's not mine either.
난 단지 여성을 보고 즐긴 것 뿐이에요
It's just that I enjoy
the female form
난 이게 위안과 오락 둘 모두를 주는
and I consider this
a victimless crime
피해자 없는 범죄라고 여기죠
that provides both
comfort and distraction.
(moaning continues)
어쩌면, 그래도 어쩌면 우리가
여기서 좀 피해줄수도 있잖아요
Maybe, uh-- maybe we can
move on from here.
고맙단 말을 해주려고
당신을 찾고 있었어요
I was looking for you
to say thank you
버스에서 내 뒤를 봐줘서 고맙다구요
for having my back at the bus.
내 목숨을 구해줬어요
You saved my life.
- 그건 몰랐는데요
- 그랬어요
- Don't know about that.
- You did.
글쎄요, 내가 그랬다면 타라가
맥락을 잘 집어줘서 가능했을거예요
Well, if I did, then you provided
the context for me doing so.
- 뭐요?
- 전 이래저래 엿된거였죠
- What?
- I was screwed either way,
그래서 전 누군가를 돕는 쪽으로
가기로 결정한거죠
so I went with the choice
that helped someone.
진부하다고 생각했지만
그게 사실이었던거죠
I thought it trite,
but it turned out to be true.
- 공은 타라거예요
- 칭찬받을만 한걸요
- Point to you.
- You have this.
전에는 그렇게 안했더라도
이렇게 해냈잖아요
Even if you didn't
before, you do.
저기 있죠, 저도...
저도 당신 같았어요
Look, I'm--
I'm the same way.
당신도 할 수 있다는걸 알잖아요
You know you can do this.
저기 내가 뭐랬는지 들었어요?
Uh, did you hear
what I just said?
버스사고는 나 때문이었어요
The bus crashed 'cause of me.
- 아녜요, 그건 아녜요
- 아뇨, 저 때문이에요
- No, it didn't.
- Yes, it did.
내가 연료관에 깨진 유리를 넣었어요
I put crushed glass
in the fuel line.
성당에서 찾은 백열구를 넣었어요
Light bulbs I found
in the church.
도로에 오르기 전에
차량이 멈췄어야 했는데
The vehicle should've failed
before it ever got to the road.
당신이 우리를 죽일뻔했어요
You would've killed us.
차가 넘어지는건 계획엔 없었어요
그 비슷하게라도요 절대, 그 반이라도요
It wasn't supposed to go down
like that, not hardly, not half.
유리를 점화 플러그 옆에있는 연료관에
The glass wasn't supposed
to wear out the fuel line
떨어트려선 안됐어요
next to the spark plugs.
운이 없게 거기 걸린거예요
We fully pulled
the short straw on that one.
지금 뭐라는?
왜 그런 짓을 한거예요?
What the hell?
Why did you do that?
유진 대체 왜...
유진?
Eugene, why did--
Eugene?
왜 그런짓을 한거예요?
Why did you do that?
- 음...
- 대답해요
- Um...
- Answer me.
긍정적인 지지와
I appreciate
the positive affirmations
변태적인 행동을
다른 시각으로 봐줘서 고마워요
and looking the other way
on the perversion,
하지만 경험으로나 최종적으로나
혼자서는 생존할 수 없어요
but I know empirically and definitively
I cannot survive on my own.
- 그럴수 없어요
- 그래서 버스를 멈추게 했다구요?
- I cannot.
- So you killed the bus?
내가 이 질병을 치료하지 못하면
If I don't cure the disease,
만약 내가 세상을 구하지 못한다면
난 아무 가치가 없으니까요
if I don't save the world,
I have no value.
- 그런다고 그렇게 되는게 아녜요
- 내가 해결하지 못한다면
- That's not how it works.
- If I don't fix things,
당신네들이 내 주변에서
머물지 않을거예요
there's no way you people
would keep me around,
자원을 공유하거나
나를 보호해주지도 않을거라구요
share resources,
even protect me.
당연히 지켜주죠
Of course we would.
우린 친구잖아요
We're friends.
우린 서로 도와줘야한다구요
그게 친구니까
We have each other's backs.
That's it.
그게 방식이에요
That's how it works.
지금 나한테 한 얘기
아무에게도 하지 말아요
Don't tell anyone else
what you did.
당신 비밀을 지켜줄게요
우리가 계속 갈 수 있도록
I'll keep your secret
and we'll keep going.
당신도 자기가 망쳤단걸 알겠지만
You know you messed up.
당신도 노력하고 있잖아요
You're trying, but, dude,
다신 그렇게 생각하지 말아요
you can't do something
like that again.
안그러죠
I won't.
이젠 어디 못가요
You're stuck with us.
우리가 당신에게 묶인 것 처럼
Just like we're stuck with you,
앞으로 어떤 일이 있어도
no matter what.
나도 왜 내가 당신에게 이런 이야길
했는지 모르겠어요
I don't know why I told you.
난 알아요
I do.
(soft laugh)
이제야 생존게임에 오셨네요
Welcome to the
human race, asshole.
가요 시간이 늦었어요
Come on.
It's getting late.
(moaning continues)
(panting, moaning increases)
후아
(sighs)
Whew.
그 사람들 생각해?
You thinkin' about them?
응
Yeah.
죄책감이 들어서
I feel guilty.
있지...
Hey.
우리 서점 바닥아래서
Hey, we get to have...
휴식을 좀 취하는 건 어때?
little vacations
on bookstore floors.
다시 그곳으로 돌아가지 않겠지
We're not back there anymore.
다른 누군가로 살게 되겠지
We're living for something else.
당장에 연락이 닿을 순 없을거야
And they don't get to right now.
음, 오늘 우리 거의 죽을뻔 했잖아
Well, we did almost die today.
게다가 차도 없고
And we don't have a car.
변기물이나 마셨지
And we're drinking toilet water.
말을 하고 나니까...
기분이 좀 나아졌어
It just feels
really good having this...
지나간 일에 관한게 아니라서
because it's not about what was.
어젯밤이 아닌
Not last night.
앞으로 어떻게 될지에 관한 일이라서
It's all about what's gonna be.
그것 때문에 죄책감 갖을 필요없어
Don't feel guilty about that.
엘렌
Ellen.
우린 이제 안전해
We're safe now.
내가 처리했어
I stopped 'em.
이제 안 무서워해도 돼
You don't have to be scared now.
저...
Hey--
괜찮아
It's okay.
(humming)
감염되진 않았네요
It's not infected.
몰래 간호학원이라도 다녔나?
You been going to nursing
school on the sly?
로저랑 팸이 가르쳐줬어요
Roger and Pam taught me.
Mm.
오늘은 여기 머무르는게 좋을 거 같아요
I think we should
stay here today.
안돼
No.
뭐 느긋하게 읽을 책이라도 많이 밀렸나?
You got some reading
you need to catch up on?
어제는 단지 운이 좋았던거라고요
We got lucky yesterday.
우리 모두 크게 부딪혔죠
특히 당신이요
But we're all banged up,
you especially.
이보다 더 안 좋은 것도 겪어왔어
We've been through worse.
계속 이동할거야
We keep moving.
우리가 언제나 100%인
상태로 출발한 적이 없어서
Maybe we always wind up stopping
늘 중간에 이렇게 멈춘건지 몰라요
because we never start at 100%.
우리가 유진박사를 워싱턴으로
늦게 데려가면 데려갈수록
Every minute we waste
getting him to Washington,
더 많은 사람들이 죽어나
people are dying.
제가 그것도 모를까봐요?
You think I don't
understand that?
결국에는
After everything?
제가 그곳에 정말 가고 싶어한다는거
잘 알잖아요?
You see, I want us
to actually get there.
아니 넌 허송 세월이나 보내려고하지
No, you want us to sit around.
넌 우리가 멈춰있길 바라는거야
You want us to stop.
(scoffs)
이 동네 그리 나쁘진 않을 거 같아
Maggie: This town
isn't in bad shape.
이 가게도 멀쩡히 있고
This store wasn't even touched.
여기를 거점으로해서
We could make a good base here.
하루 정도만 더 물자 찾으러 다녀도
될 거 같은데
We could spend one last day
doing a sweep for supplies.
그건 이동 중에 하죠
We'll sweep as we go.
휴스턴에서부터 늘 그래왔고
이제와서 쉬어가진 않아요
We've done it since Houston.
We're not stopping now.
숙녀분 말씀 들었지?
You heard the lady.
우린 북쪽으로 간다
We're taking it north.
화장실에서 확인했어요
Tara:
We tapped out the toilet.
서쪽 5마일만 가면 브로드 강이 있어요
Broad River is five miles west.
적어도 차를 찾을 때까진
거기서 물자를 비축하죠?
At the very least, we stock up
there before we find wheels.
차는 있어
We got a vehicle.
공교롭게도 말야
And it just so happens...
안에 물이 500갤런이나 있지
it's got 500 gallons
of water on it.
(humming)
(grunts)
(humming continues)
(engine whirring)
(engine starts)
(laughs)
우리가 출격하러 나가신다
About time things
started going our way!
(engine knocks, stops)
제길
Come on.
한 번이라도
Just once.
망할 한 번이라도
One damn time.
다른 차를 찾을거야
We'll find another ride.
탈만한 차가 있었다면
애초에 찾았겠지
If there was a ride worth a shit
in this town, we'd have seen it.
이건 뭐 폭동진압이라도 한 모양이야
This thing's done
some crowd clearing.
바로 여기 흡입구를 봐봐
Right up into the intake.
우리 공기여과기엔 살덩이로 꽉 차있어
Which means we've got an air filter
filled with damn human remains.
그리고 이 뭣같은 지구엔
뭣같은 코너도 남아있지 않아서
And there is no damned corner
on this damned Earth
아무리 판다고 해도 뚫리지 않을거야
that has not been dicked hard
알면 알수록 거지같구만
beyond all damned recognition.
- 아브라함
- 뭐야?
- Abraham?
- What?
거긴 라디에이터용이에요
엔진 주입구는 차 위에 있어요
That feeds the radiator. The intake for
the engine is actually on the roof.
(tire thumps)
(snarling)
타라, 매기!
Tara, Maggie!
젠장 단 한번만!
One damn time!
- 한번만 제발!
- 아브라함! 기다려!
- One damn time!
- Rosita: Abraham, just wait!
(snarling continues)
뒤쪽에 더 있어!
There's more from the back!
(growling)
(faint growling)
난 여덟번의 지역축제와
I been to eight county fairs
염소 로데오를 가봤지만
and one goat rodeo.
저런 건 한 번도 본적 없어
I never seen anything like that.
저기 서점에 굿윌이 있었어
There was a Goodwill
over there by the bookstore.
좀 너덜너덜해졌어도
물자나 마른 옷이 좀 있을지도 몰라
It's pretty blown up, but there might be
some supplies, some dry clothes, maybe?
그럴 필욘 없어
Not necessary.
단 두 방에 주입구를 뚫어주지
I can clear that intake
in two shakes.
그러면 엔진이 뚫릴거고
Then the engine
will get some wind
우린 가면 되는거야
and so will we.
몸은 그냥 말려
You'll air-dry.
우리가 간다
We roll on.
(laughing)
안에는 병자들이니
그냥 죽게 두시오
뭐?
What?
이거 아주 엿됐구먼?
This shit is screwed up!
(laughing)
(water dripping)
(gasps)
엘렌?
Ellen?
AJ?
베카야!
Becca?!
우릴 찾지 마
엘렌!
(yells) Ellen!
Ellen!
(humming)
좀 되라
- (clanking)
- Come on.
(humming continues)
(clanking continues)
난 당신 헤어스타일이
왜 그런지 알겠어요
I know why you have the haircut.
말했잖아
내가 좋아하니까
I told you,
it's 'cause I like it.
믿어주죠
저도 그 머리 좋아요
I believe that.
I like it, too.
좋아하는 이유가 있을 거 같은데
I think you like it
for a reason.
사람들이 생각하는 당신이랑
진짜 당신은 좀 다르죠
You're not the person
people think you are.
당신은 그들이
당신을 알기를 바라고 있어요
You want 'em
to know who you are.
무슨 말인지 모르겠네
Not following you.
그런 우스꽝스러운 머리를 하지 않았다면
If you didn't have that mullet,
실험실에 있는 여느 사람들이랑
똑같이 보였겠죠
you'd probably be like
everybody else in the labs.
하지만 당신은 그 사람들과는 다르죠
But you're not
like everybody else.
당신과 같은 위치에 있는 사람들은
I think a lot of people
in your position
아마 포기했을거예요
probably woulda given up,
하지만 당신은 아니죠
but you didn't.
이런 여정중에 많은 사람들이 있었고
There were people-- a lot
of them along the way--
그들은 내가 포기하지 않도록 만들었죠
they made sure I didn't give up.
나는 원래 이런 사람은 아니었어요
It wasn't me remotely.
그런걸요
It was.
당신이 이 일을 시작했죠
You started this thing.
삼손이랑은 달라요
삼손은
And you're not like Samson.
He was kind of a mess.
무슨 말인지 모르겠어
Not following you.
글쎄요, 그의 이야기는...
Well, his story goes...
어느날 사자가 그를 공격하는걸로
시작하죠
that one day
when a lion attacked him,
신은 그에게 힘을 주었고
사자를 갈기갈기 찢어버렸죠
God gave him strength
and he tore it apart.
어느날 사자 자리로 다시 돌아갔는데
물론 혼자서요
Then he goes back one day,
he's by himself,
죽은 시체에 벌들이 벌집을
지어놓은 걸 본 거예요
and he sees that bees have
made a hive in the carcass.
나중에 그는 사람들에게
수수께끼를 남겼죠
So later he tells
this riddle to people.
'먹는자에겐 먹는것이 나오고,
"Out of the eater,
something to eat.
강한자에겐 단것이 나왔느니라'
Out of the strong,
something sweet."
난, 사람들이 어떻게 그 답을 알겠어?
And I always thought, "How the hell are
people supposed to know the answer
삼손 자기밖에 모르는 일인데
when it's just
about his own life?
자기 머리에만 답이 있었잖아? 생각했어요
When the only place the answer
is is in his own head?"
워, 이거 뭐야?
Glenn:
Whoa, what the hell is that?
뭐요?
What?
바람타고 오네
곧 냄새 날거야
Wind's picking up.
You're about to smell it.
이거 무슨 냄새야?
- (all groan)
- Maggie: What is that?
뭔 악취인지는 모르겠지만
Whatever's making that stench,
참 뭐같군
it ain't nothin' nice.
멈추지 않을거야
We're not stoppin'.
어,
우린 멈췄잖아요
Uh, we're stopped.
(locusts chirping)
(wind rustling)
(coughs)
가자
Let's go.
포기하지 않을거야
- Yeah.
- Abraham: I will not lie down.
아브라함
Abraham.
쫄지 않겠어
(softly) I will not abase.
아브라함, 여기서 벗어나자구요
Abraham, let's get out of here.
난 이 차 포기 못해
I will not give up the ship.
기다려
(normal volume) Hold up.
- 우린 가야 돼
- 아니
- Maggie: We gotta go.
- No.
안 그래
No, we don't.
놈들은 우리가 들리거나 보이지도 않지
They can't hear us
and they can't see us.
여기서는 말야
Not from here.
우린 괜찮아
We're fine.
네, 이게 괜찮다라는 정의죠
Tara: Yeah, this is the
definition of fine."
지도가 필요해
분명히 우회로가 있을거야
Glenn: We need the map.
There's gotta be a detour.
아니 그렇게는 안 가
I'm not doing it.
휴스턴에서 조지아까지 우회하고
우회하고 또 우회해서 갔었어
We detoured and detoured and
detoured from Houston to Georgia.
그 지랄은 더 이상 안할거야
I'm not playing
that game anymore.
저길 지나서 가는건 아니지!
안 그래?
We are not going
through this, okay?
그건 말도 안돼
It isn't gonna happen.
우린 문 뒤에 있던 똥통도
You got a shitstorm
behind door A
다른 문 뒤에 있던 통똥도 다 겪었어
and a storm of shit
behind door B.
너만 운이 좋다면 뭐 어때 문제는 워커일 뿐인데
아님 저 망가진 트럭이겠지
If you're lucky, it's
walkers or a shot-up truck.
하지만 조만간 넌 코너에 몰릴거야
But sooner or later
you get cornered.
넌 또 머물러 있겠지
또 워커나 죽이고 있을거고
You wind up stayin'
and you wind up killin'.
돌아가지 않을거야
돌아갈 수도 없고
We don't go back.
We can't go back.
돌아가자는 말이 아냐
I'm not talking
about going back.
- 몇 마일만 남쪽으로 가잔거지
- 안돼
- Just south a few miles.
- No.
우린 이미 공기 여과기 때문에
완전 멈춘 상태입니다
Eugene: We already hit a full
stop 'cause of an air filter
내부가 완전 상했어요
compromised by innards.
계속 그럴 거예요
That will happen again.
호스로 또 뚫으면 돼
Then we'll hit 'em
with the hose.
탱크가 비었어 아브라함
Rosita: The tank
is empty, Abraham.
- 바닥까지 보면...
- 우리가 쟤넬 쳐도, 쟤들이 우리를 늦출거야
- If we floor it--
- We still hit them, they still slow us down,
그러면 저것들이 우릴 막을거야
and then they stop us.
내가 그냥 직진하자는게 아니잖아
I'm not saying
we just go straight.
길이 그렇게 나있잖아
That's the way the road goes.
- 아브라함!
- 통과 할 수 있어!
- Abraham!
- We can get through!
내가 잘 알아!
I know it!
그리고 그건 우리가 남쪽으로 가지도
And that means
we are not going south,
멀리 돌아가거나 다시 돌아가지도 않는다고!
going around, or going back!
아니에요
Rosita:
No.
이들이 맞아요
They're right.
- 이봐 아브라함
- 이봐! 어이!
- Rosita: Hey, Abraham.
- Glenn: Hey! Hey!
- 지금 뭐하는거예요? 그만 둬요
- 그거 놔요
- What are you doing? Stop.
- Glenn: Let go of him.
이렇게 두지 않을거예요
Rosita: I'm not gonna
let you do this.
- 놔 둘 수 밖에 없을걸
- 이봐요 그만하죠
- Yes, you are.
- Hey, hey, stop.
- 꺼져
- 그만 하면 됐어! 이제 됐어!
- Get out.
- Hey, you are done! You're done!
- 손 대지마! 손 대지 말라고!
- 그만해요!
- Do not! Do not!
- Stop!
내게 내 몸에 손대지 말라고 했을텐데!
내 몸에 손대지 말라고!
I told you, you do not touch me!
You do not touch me!
아브라함!
- Abraham!
- (all shouting)
아브라함!
Rosita:
Abraham!
난 과학자가 아니에요!
I'm not a scientist!
나는 과학자가 아닙니다!
내가 거짓말했어요
나는 과학자가 아니에요
I lied.
I'm not a scientist.
난 어떻게 막는줄도 모르구요
I don't know how to stop it.
과학자도 아니에요
I'm not a scientist.
당신은 과학자에요
난 당신이 할 수 있단걸 봐왔어요
You are a scientist. I've seen
the things that you can do.
그냥 몇 가지 알았던것 뿐이에요
I just know things.
지금 당신 그냥...
몇 가지 알았다구요?
You just...
"know things"?
난 내가 대부분의 사람들보다
똑똑하단걸 알았어요
I know I'm smarter
than most people,
난 거짓말을 잘하니까
I know I'm a very good liar,
내가 DC에 갈 수 있다고 생각한거예요
and I know I needed
to get to DC.
왜요?
Why?
난 거기 사람들이 수도니까
강력한 방비가 되있을거라고 생각했고
Because I do believe that locale holds
the strongest possibility for survival,
난 살고 싶었어요
and I wanted to survive.
내가 사람들을 속여서
그곳에 갈 수만 있다면
If I could cheat some people
into taking me there,
나도 그들과 함께 할 수 있을거라고
생각했어요
well, I just reasoned that
I'd be doin' them a solid, too,
휴스턴이나 다른 모든 곳들의 상태를 봐도
considering the perilous state
of the city of Houston,
다들 위험한 상황이잖아요
the state of everything.
당신을 여기까지 오게 하려고
얼마나 많은 사람들이 죽었는데요
People died
trying to get you here.
알고 있어요
I'm aware of that--
스테파니, 워렌, 팸
Stephanie, Warren, Pam,
렉스, 로져, 조쉬아,
더크 그리고 조세핀
Rex, Roger, Josiah,
Dirk, and Josephine.
그리고 밥까지
And Bob.
우리가 가까워 질 수록
나는 더 불안해 했죠
You see, I lost my nerve
as we grew closer,
나는 겁쟁인데...
(voice breaks)
for I am a coward...
현실은 목적지에 다다르고 있으니
and the reality of
getting to our destination
사실을 밝히는게
and disclosing
e truth of the matter
이렇게나 겁이 나더군요
became some
truly frightening shit.
우리의 여정을 늦추려고 내가
일을 벌렸어요
I took it upon myself
to slow our roll.
문제를 해결할 수 있는 시간을 벌고
우리가 거기 도착하는거였는데...
Find time to finesse things
so then when we got there...
하지만 이 순간
난 정말 깨달았어요
But at this moment,
I fully realize
더 이상 알맞는 옵션이 없는걸요
there are no longer
any agreeable options.
선택의 여지가 없었어요
I was screwed either way.
T.브룩스 엘리스가 제 머릴 좋아한다는
것도 거짓말이었어요
I also lied about T. Brooks
Ellis liking my hair.
난 T.브룩스 엘리스도 알지 못해요
I do not know
T. Brooks Ellis.
그저 내가 읽은 그의 책 중 하나에서
But I did read one of his
books, and he seemed like
그가 이런 타입의 사람을 좋아할지도
모른다고 생각해서 말한거예요
the type of guy that wouldn't blink
twice at a Tennessee Top Hat.
게다가...
Again...
내가 당신보다 똑똑하니까요
I am smarter than you.
이제 당신이 나를 버린대도...
Now, you may want
to leave me here--
- (gun clatters)
- (grunts)
- Hey! Hey!
- Hey, come on!
말려봐요!
- Get off of him!
- (roars)
- 세상에나
- 그러지마
- Maggie: Oh, my God.
- Glenn: No.
유진?
Maggie:
Eugene?
일어나봐요
나 좀 봐요
Get up.
Look at me.
세상에
Oh, my God.
이럴수가
유진, 내 말 들려요?
Oh, God.
Eugene, are you there?
유진!
Eugene!
유진...?
Eugene...?
정신 좀 차려봐요!
Come on!
엘렌
Abraham:
Ellen.
(dog tags rattle)
(tags clatter)
살려주세요!
Eugene:
Help me!
(snarling, growling)
사람 살려!
사람 살려요!
Help!
Help me!
(whimpers)
도와주세요 제발요!
Help me, please!
저것들이에요
없애버려요!
It's them.
Get 'em!
(growling)
죽여버려요
죽여!
Get them.
Get 'em.
고맙습니다
Thank you.
고마워요
제 생각엔... 제 생각엔
저들이 점점 빨라지는것 같아요
I think-- I think
they're gettin' faster.
잠시만요!
Wait!
기다려요!
Wait up!
멈춰봐요!
Stop!
- 그렇게 떠나지 말아요!
- 뭐요?
- You can't leave!
- Why?
내겐 엄청 중요한 임무가 있으니까요
I have a very important mission.